A Guide to the Mary S. Wood genealogical research papers, ca. 1911-2016
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Mary S. Wood genealogical research papers, ca. 1911-2016
The Library of Virginia
53076
1.35 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Mary S. Wood
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of estate of Mary S. Wood, Waynesboro, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Mary Elizabeth Shoemaker was born 5 October 1941 in Waynesboro, Virginia, to Leonard Carlyle Shoemaker (1911-1966) and Noble Robinette Herron Shoemaker (1911-2006). She graduated from Wilson Memorial High School and went to work for General Electric in Waynesboro. Mary Shoemaker married Gary Ronald Wood (1937-2005) 1 July 1961, and they had three children. Mary Wood conducted extensive genealogical research into the Shoemaker and Wood families. She died 11 April 2020, and is buried in Augusta Memorial Park.
Scope and Content
Genealogical research, ca. 1911-2016, of Mary S. Wood (1941-2020) of Waynesboro, Virginia, consisting of genealogical information on the Shoemaker/Shumaker, Wood, Baber, Hauff, Henderson, Herron, Hoy, Humphries, and Phillips, families including on lines which settled in Albemarle, Augusta, Buckingham, and Nelson Counties, and Waynesboro, Virginia. Records include articles, Bible records, books, bulletins, cds, correspondence, death certificates, emails, estate records, genealogical notes, maps, marriage bonds, notes, obituaries, photographs, wills, and other papers.
Contents List
- Shoemaker family history, by Lillian Cash, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Shoemaker family genealogical notes (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Shoemaker family genealogical notes (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Shoemaker/Shumaker genealogical notes and correspondence, 1999-2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Shumaker/Shoemaker Families of Buckingham County, Virginia, by Kimberly Shumaker Clark, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- John W. Shumaker, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jordan Wilkerson Shumaker, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jordan Wilkerson Shumaker, Jr., 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Jordan Shumaker updates, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Etta Shoemaker (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Nobel Shoemaker's 95th birthday, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Wood family genealogical notes (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Wood family genealogical notes (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Wood family photographs and information (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings, photographs and related papers of the Wood and related families (Baber, Phillips, etc.), 1911-2010 (Box 2, Folder 10)